上面说点火开关保险丝
It says the ignition switch fuse
在27号位置
is found at location number 27.
好吧  27号  我得知道那在哪
All right, 27. I need to know where that is.
就在这里
Um, right here.
好吧  这个坏了
Yeah, okay, this one's blown.
这个红色的是什么
What's this one, the red one?
爸妈  我们得走了
Mom, Dad, we got to go.
-快点  快点  -我们看见它们了
- Come on, come on. - We see them.
我们得找到保险丝来发动车
Just need to find a fuse so we can start the car.
就快找到了  亲爱的  6号位置
Almost got it, honey. Location six.
那里有转向灯和刹车灯
That's turn signal lamps and stop lamps.
没有转向灯也行
All right, we can live without turn signals.
爸  它们来...
Dad, they're com--
《行尸走肉》
(西芹汤)
西芹汤
Celery soup.
放在这里一直没人要
It's been here since the start.
你真勇敢
You're very brave.
我希望辣椒粉能掩盖
Well, I'm hoping the paprika will mask
汤里的西芹味
the soup's celeryness.
那你就会做出一碗辣椒粉汤
Then you'd be stuck with something that tastes like paprika.
还是不要了
No, thank you.
我只是想着既然我们的主食不多了
Well, I just figured since we're running low on staples,
我想用一些没人想要的东西
I'd try to use a few things nobody seems to want.
我以前会给爱德做春季大扫荡砂锅菜
I used to make Ed these spring cleaning casseroles
就是为了清空储藏室
just to empty the pantry.
我靠荸荠制造过奇迹
I made some miracles happen with water chestnuts.
说到奇迹  可乐罐头火腿的食谱真了不起
Talk about miracles, that recipe for cola canned ham.
佩尔蒂埃太太  你真是个大英雄
Ms. Peletier, you are an honest to goodness hero.
有什么问题吗  谢莉
Something wrong, Shelly?
只是一些老面条
It's just those old noodles.
我跟你说
I mean, I tell you,
如果有人给我找到一台机器
if someone would just find me one of those machines,
我发誓我们会大吃特吃意面
I swear we would all be eating like we were on a tour of Tuscany.
小谢  我可以教你
You know, Shel, I could teach you
怎么用双手做意面
how to make pasta with your own two hands.
但你得保证别在房子里抽烟
But you'd have to promise not to smoke in the house.
那是个令人讨厌的习惯
It's just a disgusting habit.
而且会害死你
And it kills you.
要我说  已经有太多
If you ask me, there are too many things
想害死你的东西了  对吧
trying to do that already, right?
对
Right.
你爸爸以前打你  然后他被人杀了
Your dad used to hit you and then he got himself killed.
这事发生了  别多想了
It happened. Now it's done.
你要么接受这一点  要么被打垮
You live with it or it eats you up.
回家吧
Go home.
罗恩
Ron.
你能下来吗
Can you come down here?
不
No.
-罗恩  -不  我不想剪头发
- Ron. - No, I don't want a haircut.
瞧  我刚给自己剪了  好吗
Look, I just gave myself one. All right?
东西都摆好了  别逼我下周再摆一次
It's all set up. Don't make me do it again next week.
摘下你的帽子
Take off your hat.
-这太扯了  -你说什么...
- This is bullshit. - What did you just--
你不过是想和我谈谈
This is just you trying to talk to me.
有些事情我们得谈谈了
There are things we need to talk about.
有些事情你必须学
There are things that you need to learn.
什么  你认真的吗
What, are you serious?
到底怎么了  你是...你是在怪我吗
What is it? Do you-- do you blame me?
你真的在怪我吗
Do you actually blame me?
把你的左臂举过头顶
Raise your left arm above your head.
你做不到  告诉我为什么
You can't. Tell me why.
不
No.
你爸很危险
Your father was dangerous.
瑞克很危险
Rick is dangerous.
他和这件事没关系
He doesn't have anything to do with this.
怎么  他是你的朋友吗
What, is he your friend?
没错  他是我的朋友
Yeah, he's my friend.
板子可以后搭
We got some panels to put up,
但我们可以先种东西
but we don't have to wait to start growing things.
你会累得腰酸腿疼
There will be some sore backs and tired feet.
辛苦劳作就是这样
That's how you know you've put in a hard day's work.
他们在几里外的一个育苗场里找到了好几箱种子
They found crates of these at a nursery just a few miles out.
西红柿  胡萝卜  什么都有
Tomatoes, carrots, you name it.
我们可以在这里种
We can plant them right here.
只需要完成扩张
Just need to finish the expansion
并且把墙建起来
and the wall needs to go up.
雷吉希望这个社区能壮大
Reg wanted this community to grow.
你也是这么希望的
You did, too.
现在改变主意了吗
Has that changed?
这里所有人都是因为你才在这里的
Everyone that's here is here because of you.
你得让他们看到你的心还在这里
You need to show them you're still here.
我只是说那让我爽歪歪
It hams my biscuits is all.
而且根据体积计算
And going by cubic feet,
那是扩张区中最大的一栋建筑物
the biggest building in the expansion
而我们却要把它浪费在一座教堂上
and we're gonna waste it on a church.
把那些长椅拆掉
Take out the benches,
那里就可以变成一间实验室
that could be a lab,
或者一个车间
a machine shop,
至少可以变成一间超赞的游戏室
very least a sweet-ass game room.
墙内房产在这里是非常珍贵的
Walled-in real estate is at a premium here.
神棍不应该有优先权
Thumpers just shouldn't get dibs.
也许我们可以共用教堂
Well, maybe we share the church, you know?
每天做不同的用途
Do all that stuff on different days.
让你爽歪歪吗
Hams my biscuits?
爽歪歪  我只听到了这个
Hams my biscuits. That's all I heard.
我完全不知道你之后说了什么
I mean, I have no idea what you said after that.
-我说根据体积...  -我开玩笑的
- Going by cubic feet... - I was kidding.
你还好吧  丹娜
Are you okay, Dana?
-我叫丹妮斯  -丹妮斯  不好意思
- It's Denise. - Denise, I'm sorry.
没关系
I'm okay.
我是新任医生
I'm the new doctor now.
你拿阿司匹林做什么
What's the aspirin for?
-你是医生吗  -那你是吗
- You're a doctor? - Are you?
抱歉  我...
I'm sorry. I, uh...
之前听说过你的事
heard that story.
黑得漂亮
Fair play.
听着  其实我有点紧张
Listen, I'm a little nervous here.
我是心理医生
I'm a psychiatrist.
读医学院那会儿
I went to med school.
我本打算当外科医生
I was even gonna be a surgeon,
但结果惊恐发作
but after the panic attacks,
从此便对心理学感兴趣了
I got really interested in psychology.
其实...
And...
我只想让你们别对我抱太大期望
I think I'm really trying to lower expectations here.
你到底行不行
Can you do this?
尤金  闭嘴  她能行的
Eugene, shut up. She can do this.
全镇只有我一个人能上
I'm all this town's got.
皮特不想我干这个
Pete didn't want me here.
但我却来了
But I'm here now
不过还是会时不时想吐
and I only kind of want to throw up.
那你拿阿司匹林做什么
So why the aspirin?
我和尤金正在搭建另一座哨塔
Eugene and I were working on a platform for another guard tower.
我有点头晕  毕竟头痛还没有全好
I got a little dizzy. You know, I still get headaches.
坐吧  我帮你看看
Sit down, I'll take a look.
你是我的第一位患者
You're my first patient.
这点小毛病  我保证医不死你
And with that symptom, I'm pretty sure I can't kill you.
除非有类似血肿什么的
I mean, it is possible if you miss,
你没有检查出来
like, a hematoma or something.
卡尔
Carl?
干嘛
What?
你知道我跟迪安娜告密了
You heard what I told Deanna about your group.
你想干什么
What do you want?
那怪我
It was about me,
与你  和你们团队无关
not you or your group.
我如今醒悟了
I know that now.
我想帮忙
I want to help.
在教堂的时候  我不让你教我
You tried to teach me back at my church.
但现在我想学了
But I'm ready to learn now.
你应该把这个想法告诉大家
I think you need to tell everybody.
对  你说得没错
Yeah, I think you're right.
三点左右过来吧
Come by around 3:00.
我们先从砍刀学起
We'll start with the machete.
理查兹  发生了什么事
Richards. What's going on in there?
不
Oh, no.
No.
快走
Come on!
我从楼上看到了
I saw from upstairs.
他们正从四周突袭进来
They're coming in from all over.
你必须留在这保护朱迪思
You have to stay here and keep Judith safe.
-求你别走  -我必须去找罗恩
- Please don't go. - I have to go find Ron.
求你了  别走
Please. Please don't go.
-我马上就回来  好吗  -妈  不
- I'm gonna be right back, okay? - Mom, no.
你藏到衣橱里
You go put yourself in the closet
锁好门栓  就像我教你的那样
and you close the latch just like I showed you.
你好
Hi.
你怎么不敲门
Why didn't you just knock?
我有钥匙  不想让那些人拿到
I have these. Didn't want them to have them.
我想跟你道别
And I wanted to say good-bye.
看好后门  看到他们过来就告诉我
Okay, watch the back door. Tell me if you see them coming.
-我要走了  -你不能走
- I'm not staying. - You're not going anywhere.
坐下  帮我一起保护朱迪思
Sit down. You're helping me protect Judith.
他们不能踏进这房子
They're not getting inside this house.
我们不许
We're not gonna let them.
看到他们了吗
Did you see them?
他们只不过是人
They're just people.
这地方太大了  保护不了的
This place is too big to protect.
盲点太多了
There are too many blind spots.
所以我们才能...
That's how we were able to...
墙没拦住他们  但是他们会死的
They got in the walls, but they're gonna die.
都会死
All of them.
别跟我道别
Don't tell me good-bye.
好吧
Okay.
我不会的
I won't.
不  请别这样
No, please. Please don't.
不  求你了  求你了
No, please. Please...
走开
Go away!
天啊
Oh, God.
该死
Shit.
快啊  快啊
Come on. Come on.
霍莉
Holly!
准备手术台
We need the operating table prepped.
她失血很多  快  快  快
She's lost a lot of blood. Come on, come on, come on.
闯进来多少人
How many people are out there?
我不知道  很多
I don't know, there's a lot.
罗西塔  你知道怎么静脉注射吗
Rosita, you know how to stick an IV?
我来  给我纱带
I'm on it. Here, hand me tape.
好
Got it.
怎么响汽笛了  到底怎么回事
What about the air horn? What's happening?
我不知道  我得去帮忙
I don't know. I need to help.
-我必须试试  -我知道
- I need to try. - I know.
丹妮斯  我也必须过去了
Denise, I'm gonna have to go, too.
我也是
So do I.
你挥舞锤子都会头晕
You got dizzy swinging a hammer.
必须有人看守住这个地方
Somebody's got to guard this place.
-你能行的  -我不行
- You can handle it. - I can't!
我认为此时此刻
I also believe my services
我待在这里最有用
would be best rendered right very here.
-什么  -我认为此时此刻...
- What? - I also believe my services--
闭嘴  你在这很安全  走
Shut up! You're safe here. Come on.
怎么回事
What happened?
有一伙人  闯进了墙内
Someone, a group, they got inside the walls.
他们在大肆屠杀
They're killing people.
我们得进去
We need to get in there.
你来吗
You coming?
躲起来
Hide.
想快点死
Quick...
还是慢点死
or slow?
请你
Leave.
离开
Please.
那就是慢点死
Gonna be slow.
我能阻止他的
I could have stopped him.
-其他人回来了吗  -没有
- The others back? - No.
-他们正在行动  -他们现在就动手了吗
- It's happening out there. - They're doing it now?
不得不动手
We had to.
这些人没有枪
These people don't have guns.
我能阻止他的
I could have stopped him.
他们要是有枪  就会用
If they had guns, they'd be using them.
你听到我的话了吗
Did you hear me?
我们得抢先到达军械库
We have to get to the armory before they do.
要是我们快点  说不定能成功
If we keep moving, this might work.
你没必要杀人
You don't have to kill people.
当然有必要了
Of course we do.
卡萝尔
Carol!
你不喜欢这样
You don't like it.
我得赶到军械库  我需要你的帮助
I'm gonna get to the armory and I need your help.
妈
Mom!
天啊  斯宾塞
Oh, God. Spencer.
感谢上帝
Thank God.
我们得进去
We need to get inside.
我不能进去  我没有枪
I can't go in there. I don't have a gun.
我不知道怎么战斗
I don't know how to fight.
要是我进去
If I go inside,
只会变成你们的累赘
I'll just be another person who's got to be saved.
现在我能为里面的人做的最好的事
The best thing that I can do for everyone in there
就是待在外面
is to stay out here.
-保护好她  -好的
- Keep her safe. - I will.
她怎么了
What's happening with her?
她在内出血
She's bleeding internally.
也许切到了股动脉
Probably severed her femoral artery.
她快死了
She's dying.
好吧  切到了动脉  能治好吗
Okay, so the artery's severed. Can it be fixed?
外科医生也许可以
Maybe by a surgeon.
你本来要成为外科医生的
You were gonna be a surgeon.
但我不是
But I'm not.
她保护着这个地方
She was protecting this place.
她守护着我们
She was guarding us.
这就是我们在这里的原因  照顾彼此
That's why we're here, for each other.
你害怕了吗
You're afraid?
我不在乎  救救她
I don't care. Help her.
试一下
Try!
救她
Help her!
你不想当一个懦夫的
You don't want to be a coward.
我懂的
I know.
我需要一根束腹带
I need an abdominal binder.
我们要把刀拔出来
We're gonna pull the knife.
好的
Okay. Okay.
妈的
Shit!
求你了
Please, man.
求你别杀我  求你了
Please don't kill me, man. Please.
求你救救我  我的腿
Help me, please. My leg.
回屋里
Come inside.
我可以保护你
I can keep you safe.
不
No.
罗恩
Ron.
卡尔  进来
Carl, come on!
妈
Mom.
妈  你在家吗
Mom, you in?
锁起来  勇敢点
Lock it. Be brave.
别进来  罗恩
Stay outside, Ron!
不
No!
干得好  蚜虫
Good catch, Aphid.
快走
Come on.
-别管他了  -不
- Leave him. - No.
蚜虫  从哪拿的枪
Hey, Aphid, where'd you get the gun?
你死定了
You're dead.
求你别杀我
Please don't kill me.
没事的  还有人在这吗
It's okay. Anybody else down here?
-奥利维亚  -没了
- Olivia! - No.
没了  就我一个
No, I'm the only one.
过来
Come here.
快点
Now.
我一走你就守住我身后的门
You barricade that door behind me once I leave.
知道怎么开枪吗
Do you know how to shoot a gun?
站在这
Stand here.
手指扣扳机  对准那边
Finger here. Aim there.
有敌人进来
One of them comes through that door,
就一直扣扳机  直到他们倒地
you squeeze and you don't stop till they're on the ground.
你的招数是哪儿学的
How did you learn how to do that?
一个做奶酪的人教我的
From a cheese maker.
我们是在解放你们
We're freeing you.
你们被困住了
You're trapped.
你们得知道  人们不再属于这里了
You need to know, people don't belong here anymore.
-卡萝尔  -玛姬
- Carol? - Maggie!
-给  -我...
- Here. - I--
我不大会用枪  我...
I'm not very good with guns. I--
我也是
Me neither.
是你
You.
你住在这里吗
You live here?
离开吧
Leave.
我的伙伴有枪
My people have guns.
你的伙伴没有
Yours don't.
他们可能正端着步枪瞄准你们
They may be aiming rifles at you right now.
眼睛盯着瞄准具
Eyes at the scopes.
手指扣着扳机
Fingers on the trigger.
砰
Boom.
他们随时会开枪
It's gonna happen any second now
除非你们离开这里  再也别回来
unless you get the hell out of here and you don't ever come back.
你们继续选择这种生活
You keep choosing this life,
迟早要送命的
you will die.
不是我们选择的
We didn't choose.
醒醒啊  霍莉
Come on, Holly.
丹妮斯  你尽力了
Denise, you tried.
你是医生
You are a doctor.
去看看外面结束了没有
Just go see if it's over out there
如果...
and if...
请你们都走吧
Please go, all of you.
-好吧  但我只是  -好  走吧
- Okay, but I just-- - Good. Go.
我只想说...
All I was gonna say is...
记得破坏她的大脑
make sure you get her brain.
今天发生的事
What happened today,
外面就是这样吗
that's what it's like out there?
差不多吧
Pretty much.
你们怎么
How do you--
你们知道世界是那样的  还怎么活着啊
how do you just live knowing that's the world?
为了这个团队
This group,
为了亚伯拉罕  还有这地方
Abraham, and this place.
确保你有值得为之牺牲的东西
Make sure you got something worth dying for.
我们还活着呢
We're still here.
并非所有人
Not all of us.
伊妮德
Enid?
(无论如何都要活下去)
你狠不下心  对吧
You can't, can you?
你该狠心的
You should've.
抱歉
I'm sorry.